Here, I'll step through the arm_mover code and explain what's going on.
ここでは arm_mover コードを実施して何が起こっているのかを説明します
The imported modules for arm_mover are the same as
arm_mover 用にインポートされたモジュールは 2 つの新しいインポートを除いて
simple_arm with the exception of two new imports.
simple_arm と同じです
Namely, the joint state message and the simple Arm Service Module.
ジョイント状態メッセージと単純なアーム サービス モジュールです
Joint state messages are published to the simple_arm/joint_states topic,
ジョイント状態メッセージはsimple_arm / joint_statesトピックに発行され
and are used for monitoring the position of the arm.
アームの位置を監視するために使用されます
The simple arm package and the service module,
シンプルなアーム パッケージとサービ スモジュール
SRV, are automatically generated by Catkin as part of the build process.
SRV は ビルド プロセスの一部として Catkin によって自動的に生成されます
The app goal function returns true if the joint positions are close to the goals.
ジョイント位置が目標に近い場合aｔ_goal関数はtrueを返します
When taking measurements from sensors in the real world,
リアルワールドでセンサ-を扱う場合
there'll always be some amount of noise.
いくらかのノイズが発生します
The same is true for joint positions reported by the gazebos simulator.
Gazebos シミュレーターによって報告されたジョイント位置についても同じことが言えます
If both positions are within 0.05 radians of the goal, true is returned.
両方の位置がゴールの 0.05 ラジアン以内であれば true が返されます
The clamp and boundaries function is responsible for
clamp_at_bundaries()関数は
enforcing the minimum and maximum joint angles for each joint.
各ジョイントの最小ジョイント角と最大ジョイント角を制約する役目を担います
If the joint angles passed are outside of the operable range,
通過したジョイント角度が操作可能範囲外の場合
they'll be clamped to the nearest allowable value.
アームは最も近い許容値に固定されます
The minimum and maximum joint angles are retrieved from the parameter server,
最小ジョイント角および最大ジョイント角がパラメーター サーバーから検索され
each time clamp and boundaries is called.
境界でclamp関数が毎回呼び出されます
The Tildy here is the private namespace qualifier,
Tildy ～はプライベート空間名を表す(ユーザのホームディレクトリ)を示す
and indicates that the parameter which we wish to get is within the node's namespace.
取得したいパラメーターがノードの名前空間内にあることを示します
For example, here it's /simple_ arm/.
たとえば ここでは /simple_ arm/です
The second parameter is the default value to be returned in the case
2 番目のパラメーターは
that rospy.get_param was unable to get the parameter from the param server.
rospy.get_param がパラメーター サーバーからパラメーターを取得できなかった場合に返されるデフォルト値です
The rest of this function simply clamps the joint angle if necessary.
この関数の残りは必要に応じて 単にジョイント角を固定します
Warning messages are logged if the requested joint angles are out of bounds.
要求されたジョイント角が範囲外の場合 警告メッセージがログに記録されます
The move arm function commands the arm to move,
move arm 関数は アームに移動を命令し
returning the amount of time that elapsed while the arm was moving.
アームが動いている間に経過した時間を返します
Note. Within the function we are using the rospy.wait_for_message
注記関数内では
call to receive joint_state messages from the /simple_arm/joint_states topic.
/simple_arm /joint_states トピックからjoint_statesのメッセージを受信するために、rospy.wait_formessegeの命令を使用しています
This is a blocking function call.
この関数はブロッキング コールバックと呼ばれます
Meaning that it will not return until a message has been
これは simple arm/joint states トピックでメッセージが受信されるまで
received on the simple arm/joint states topic.
メッセージは返されないことを意味します
In general, you should not use wait_for_message.
通常は wait_for_message は使用しないでください
We simply use it here for the sake of clarity and because move_arm is being called from
ここでは、(皆さんに)わかりやすく伝えるために使用しますが move_armが
the handle_safe_move_request function which demands
handle_safe_move_request 関数から呼び出されます
that the response message is passed back as a return parameter.
この関数は 応答メッセージは戻りパラメーターとして返されます
We'll talk more about this in a moment.
この点については後で詳しく説明します
This is the service handler function.
この関数は service handler 関数です
When a service client sends
サービス クライアントが
a GoToPositionRequest to the safe_move service this function is called.
GoToPositionRequest を safe_move service に送信すると この関数が呼び出されます
The function parameter REQ or request is a type
関数パラメーター REQ または要求が
GoToPositionRequest the service response is a type GoToPositionResponse.
GoToPositionRequest タイプの場合 サービス応答のタイプは GoToPositionResponse となります
This service function handler is called whenever a new service request is received.
このサービス関数ハンドラーは 新しいサービス要求が受信されるたびに呼び出されます
The response to the service request is returned from the function.
サービス要求に対する応答は関数から返されます
Another note here.
もう 1 つの注記です
The move arm function is blocking and
move arm 関数がブロックしており
will not return until the arm has finished its movement.
アームの移動が終了する前 応答を返しません
Incoming messages cannot be processed and no other useful work
アームが移動命令を実行中は 受信メッセージを処理することはできず
can be done in the python script while the arm is performing its movement command.
他の有用な作業を Python スクリプト内で行うことができません
While this poses no real problem for
この例に関しては何の問題もないですが
this example it is a practice that should generally be avoided.
通常は 避けるべき作業です
One great way to avoid blocking the threat of
実行スレッドのブロッキングを回避するためのすぐれた方法の 1 つは
execution would be to use an action rather than a service.
Serviceの代わりにActionを使用することです
You can find some more information about when it's best to use
以下のリンクにおいて
a topic versus a service versus an action in the links below.
トピック対サービス、またトピック対アクションをいつ使用するのが最適かについての詳細な情報を見つけることができます
Here the node is initialized with the name arm_mover
arm moverという名前でノードは初期化されており
and the GoToPositionService is created with the name safe_move.
safe moveという名前で GoToPositionService が作成されています
As mentioned previously the Tildy qualifier identifies
上記のように Tildy
that safe_move is meant to belong to the nodes private namespace.
修飾子はsafe_moveがノードのプライベート名前空間に属することを意味します
The resulting service name will be /arm_mover/safe_move.
結果的に サービス名は /arm_mover/safe_move となります
The thirm parameter to the
rospy.serve_call への3番目のパラメータは
rospy.service_call is the function
rospy.service_call への thrim パラメーターは
that should be called when a service request is received.
サービス要求を受信したときに呼び出す必要がある関数です
Lastly, rospy.spin simply blocks until the shutdown request is received by the node.
最後に rospy.spin はシャットダウン要求がノードによって受信されるまでブロックします
Failure to include this line would result in
この行を入れない場合
mover_service returning and the script completing execution.
mover_service が返され スクリプトの完了の実行が失敗します
Finally, we have the if_name_=_main block.
最終的に if_name_=_main block となります
This section of code is similar to that of simple_mover.
このコード セクションは simple_mover のセクションと似ています